# Wladimir Sawicki

Moscow, Moscow City, Russia



linkedin.com/in/wladimir-sawicki-16761499



vladimir.slepovron@gmail.com

### Summary

Frontend developer with a long experience in system administration and IT analytics. Worked in both large companies and small businesses (including freelancing and volunteering).

Ready to relocate to Poland (also considering proposals for a remote job).

#### Experience



#### Frontend Developer

#### Self-employed

Dec 2018 - Present (1 year 9 months +)

Frontend developer. Creation and make changes to web applications on request. Use the following knowledge and tools:

- JavaScript ES5 / ES6+ (asynchronous requests, modular structure),
- Version control system: Git (cli default command),
- Understanding the work of the TCP/IP (OSI) protocol stacks,
- Module bundler: Webpack (with JS compiler: Babel),
- Basic knowledge of library React.js,
- HTML5 / CSS3 (Flexbox and Grid layout, Bootstrap4, Boilerplate, AnimateCSS, etc.),
- Job experience with web servers: Node.JS, XAMPP (lamp), IIS, NGINX,
- Code editors: VSCode, Sublime Text, Atom,
- Operating systems: Windows / Windows Server (system and network administrator), Linux Mint / Parrot Security / Ubuntu (user),
- Understanding the structure of information security of web applications (within the frames of "OWASP top 10").

As a basic knowledge of the network structure, I draw on the long experience of a systems administrator and IT analyst (also including the management of the IT security infrastructure).



### System Administrator / Information Security Specialist

"Houston" system administration team

Feb 2016 - Dec 2018 (2 years 11 months)

- System Administrator / Information Security Specialist
- Deployment and support of domain structures based on Microsoft Server 2008r2 (ADDS, WSUS, DHCP, DNS, GPMC, FS, TS, FTPS, etc. support and development of the existing LAN/WAN infrastructure),
- Organization of the relocation of IT infrastructure (work planning and support for the restoration of the IT structure without compromising the business process),
- Information security both within the domain policies and for the protection of personal data top clients (including training of users on the basic information security of the company and personal information),
- Interaction with companies that provide pentesting and secure correspondence services, as well as with authorities that monitor compliance with the GDPR.

As additional skills I can specify:

- Information security (including mobile security) and personal data protection. I actively participate in specialized conferences and training sessions from manufacturers of forensic solutions, specialists in pentest and ethical hacking (Elcomsoft, Oxygen Software, Electronic Cloud, TMGroup).
- Understand the structure of blockchains and distributed ledgers (both in terms of financial interaction crypto asset, and in terms of business technologies).
- Trading and financial market analysis based on technical analysis. Work with financial assets of crypto market, exchanges, fiat gateways.

#### Sr. IT Infrastructure Analyst, Eastern Europe

#### Avon

Dec 2014 - Dec 2015 (1 year 1 month)

- Senior IT Infrastructure Analyst, Eastern Europe (Senior System Administrator)
- Domain forest based on Microsoft Server 2008r2 (ADDS, WSUS, DHCP, DNS, GPMC, FS, TS, FTPS, etc. support and development of the existing LAN/WAN infrastructure), equipment HP, Dell, IBM, Cisco,
- Server virtualization based on VMware VSphere,
- Backup and recovery systems: Symantec Backup Exec, Veeam,
- Monitoring systems: Nagios, IBM Tivoli,
- Websense network security solution,
- TrendMicro antivirus software,
- Video and audio conference: Polycom Telepresence, MS Lync / Skype for business, Adobe Connect,
- Avaya Aura PBX,
- CRM services: Hardware Inspector, Remedy, IBM Notes/Domino, OTRS,
- Office equipment: Xerox, HP, Konica Minolta, Kyocera.

#### Participation in projects and activities:

- Support of the global project on transition from Windows Server 2003 to Windows Server 2008r2 / Windows Server 2012r2 at the regional level
- Elimination of the global problem of unauthorized access to the Internet by users in a workplace with terminal access
- Development and implementation of the global policy for using of the file servers,
- Introduction of secure printing using SafeQ technology,
- Development, coordination and implementation of the correct standard transliteration of Cyrillic usernames,
- Conducting the activity for safe use of the Internet traffic created by users on remote production sites

### System administrator, IT manager.

#### Self employ

Sep 2013 - Jun 2014 (10 months)

IT freelance in a foreign country (Vietnam, Thailand).

- Search for clients (hostels, restaurants, private clients),
- Configuration and support of local networks and network equipment, backup organisation, search and elimination of the causes of failures, information security,
- Recommendations for repair and replacement of equipment.

#### Senior System Administrator

«Oboronenergo» open joint-stock company

Jan 2011 - Jul 2013 (2 years 7 months)

- Senior System Administrator (7 employees, 5 units, 18 servers, 800 users)

- Domain forest based on Microsoft Server 2008R2-2012R1 (ADDS, RODC, IIS, FTP, WSUS, Hiper-V, DHCP, DNS, GPMC, FS, TS, organization structure and replication OU), equipment HP ProLiant DL 160/360, Dell, Depo, IBM,
- Network equipment: HP, 3com, Netgear, ZyXEL, D-Link, TP-link (VLAN, WDS)
- Gateway Kerio Control 8 (NAT, PAT, VPN, Kerio-VPN, L2TP, PPPoE),
- NAS servers on the basis of Netgear, QNAP,
- Panasonic PBX: KX-TDA100, KX-TDE100, KX-TDE200, IP-PBX Asterisk (Elastix), Free-PBX,
- Video and audio conference: Panasonic Communication Assistance, MS Lync 2010, Skype, Google Hangouts
- Legos ACS Access control system (implementation, configuration, programming, access zone)
- CRM systems: Hardware Inspector, OTRS, 1C EDS
- The backup: Acronis Backup, Acronis True Image,
- Implementation of 1C Enterprise 8.1 (SCP and Workflow) training,
- Staff Cop Standard monitoring system,
- Office equipment: Konica Minolta, HP, Kyocera,
- Network design and putting into service,
- Interaction with counterparts
- Maintenance of applicants new IT staff (interview, hiring / firing, etc.).

I have got a reference letter written by the Company General Director and it can be provided if required

### **System Administrator**

Foundation "Institute for Urban Economics"

Jul 2010 - Dec 2010 (6 months)

- Domain structure based on Microsoft Server (Windows Server 2003, AD, File Server, DNS, DHCP, GPO etc.) and end-user support (Windows XP / Vista / Se7en, Windows Mobile 6 / 6.1 / 6.5)
- MDaemon mail server administration,
- Remote access and user support (VNC, DameWare, Team Viewer),
- Working with established bank customers (Sberbank, Taxcom),
- Support internal telephony (Panasonic TDE 100)
- Administration of systems of corporate security, anti-virus applications, firewalls (Kerio Control, NOD32),
- Administration of OS Microsoft SQL Server 2000 2005,
- Installing and configuring the operating system Microsoft Windows XP Windows 7, office applications, Microsoft Office 2003 2010, OpenOffice,
- Working with contractors (equipment suppliers, mobile operators, service providers, technical services related to IT),
- Maintain of IT documentation (application users, preparation of tenders for the purchase of equipment and software, contracts with contractors).

#### Senior IT Specialist

Uralsib

Dec 2009 - May 2010 (6 months)

- Technical support and solution of problems of internal and external users of the bank in HP OpenView Service Desk.
- Support of legal entities and individuals operating in the BS-client.
- Advised customer support users remote banking services ("e-customer", "Internet Service Bank", "Uralsib +"), support of IT-structures of the bank clients in resolving issues on work with the services of the company.

# System Administrator

"Tupperware" LLC

May 2008 - Sep 2009 (1 year 5 months)

- Administration of domain structure based on Microsoft Server (Windows Server 2003, AD, File Server, DNS, DHCP, GPO etc.) and end-user support (Windows XP Pro, XP Home, Win7, Windows Mobile 6 / 6.1 / 6.5)
- Backup and Data Recovery (Veritas backup),
- Support of internal PBX (Avaya),
- Interaction with contractors (equipment suppliers, mobile operators, service providers, technical services related to IT),
- Maintain IT documentation (application users, equipment purchases, contracts with contractors)
- Introduction of user requests (problems, requests for equipment, IT support activities undertaken by the company, Skype conferences).

## Assistant System Administrator / System Administrator

"Houston" system administration team

Oct 2006 - Apr 2008 (1 year 7 months)

- Administration of LAN (Windows Server 2003, AD, DNS, DHCP, configure user groups and security policies)
- Advice and support for end-users (Windows 95, 98, 2000, XP, Vista),
- Installation work on the development and renewal of the network (Ethernet, Wi-Fi),
- Check assembly connecting and configuring newly purchased equipment,
- Installation and update of anti-virus software on machines of end-users and updating anti-virus databases on the server (Symantec, KAV, AVG, Avast),
- Maintenance and inventory of office equipment,
- Maintaining a database of user requests and database for the purchase of new equipment.

#### Education



#### **Tula State University**

Specialist (5 years), "Electricity supply"

2000 - 2005

- Conducting classes in sports Irish dance, organizing performances and preparing for exams,
- Historical and social dances, analysis of schemes and figures, preparation of musical part, participation in historical festivals.

# Technical College. S.I. Mosin of Tula State University

electrical engineer, "Electricity supply of industrial enterprises and civil structures" 1996 - 2000

#### **Skills**

JavaScript • NodeJS • Git • Engineering • TCP/IP • ITIL • Project Management • Dynamic Host Configuration Protocol (DHCP) • Domain Name System (DNS) • Microsoft Technologies